Michael Alpert collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Leon Schwartz recordings
  - Leon Schwartz- II, January 21, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0088; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Leon and Charlotte Schwartz's home.; Alpert 157-158; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- "Like in a Different World", February 19, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0089; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 159-160; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- "Like in a Different World" (Copy), February 19, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0656; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 159-160; 1 sound cassette
  - Burekh Schwartz, August 18, 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0090; Personnel: Burekh Schwartz, Ya'akov Mazor, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Chez Lui, 14 Frankfurter St. P.T.; Alpert 161-162; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz Compendium Work Tape, Bronya Sakina, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0091; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert; Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, Bronya Sakina.; Alpert 163-164; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz Work Tape, Bronya Sakina, ca. 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0092; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert; Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, Bronya Sakina.; Alpert 165-166; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0093; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 167-168; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0094; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Charlotte Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 169-170; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0095; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 171; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, mastered, 1987-08, AFC 2017/048: SR0097; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, et al.; Recording location: Stephen Erickson Studio.; Alpert 174-175; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, mastered, February 2, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0098; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, et al.; Recording location: Stephen Erickson Studio.; Alpert 176-177; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz reel 1, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0099; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, et al.; Alpert 178; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz reel 2, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0100; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, et al.; Alpert 179; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz out takes, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0101; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, et al.; Alpert 180; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, mixed and mastered material, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0102; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, et al.; Alpert 181-182; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- From our Mr Schwartz, July 28, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0103; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 183-184; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- From our Mr Schwartz (Copy), July 28, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0657; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 183-184; 1 sound cassette
  - Radio show, side B, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0104; Personnel: various.; Alpert 185; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, vox clips I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0105; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 186; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, vox clips II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0106; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 187; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, vox clips III, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0107; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 188; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, vox clips IV, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0108; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 189; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz et al, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0109; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, et al.; Alpert 190-191; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0410; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 782; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz and Bronya Sakina Compendium, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0432; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Bronya Sakina.; Alpert 820-821; 1 sound cassette
  - Vox Clips, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0647; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 1150-1151; 1 sound cassette
  - Digital surrogates of recordings in Series 2, 1979-1992, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 146 WAV, 146 MP3, 71 PDF
- Series 3: German Goldenshteyn
  Conversations, interviews, rehearsals, and performances with German Goldenshteyn (1934-2006), a klezmer clarinetist from Otaci, Romania (now a part of Moldova). Goldenshteyn immigrated to the United States in 1994. Included in this series are performances for the New England Conservatory Intercultural Institute Klezmer Workshop. Mina Goldenshteyn also participated in many of the conversations.
  There are no digital surrogates for AFC 2017/048: SR0626 and SR0627.
  - Brooklyn Sov Jew Swamp Opera, April 15, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0001; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn (clarinet), Hersch Rikelman (accordion), Yidl Aslavinsky (violin), Rakhmiel Bilinson (garmoshka), Boris Pevsner (voice).; Recording location: Masores Bais Yaakov School Hall, 1395 Ocean Avenue, Brooklyn, NY.; Alpert 001-002; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, April 23, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0110; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, J. Wollock, K. Bjorling (tsimbl), Michael Alpert, Willy Schwartz (accordion).; Alpert 192-193; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn (Copy), April 23, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0658; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, J. Wollock, K. Bjorling (tsimbl), Michael Alpert, Willy Schwartz (accordion).; Alpert 192-193; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, May, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0111; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 194-195; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Klava Rosentul, 1999-2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0112; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Klava Rosentul, Zev Feldman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 196; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Klava Rosentul (Copy), 1999-2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0659; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Klava Rosentul, Zev Feldman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 196; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Yosef Kagansky- I, July, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0114; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Yosef Kagansky, Hankus Netsky, Jeffrey Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: New England Conservatory Intercultural Institute- Intensive Klezmer Workshop.; Alpert 198-199; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Yosef Kagansky- II, July, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0115; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Yosef Kagansky, Hankus Netsky, Jeffrey Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: New England Conservatory Intercultural Institute- Intensive Klezmer Workshop.; Alpert 200-201; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Yosef Kagansky- III, July, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0116; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Yosef Kagansky, Hankus Netsky, Jeffrey Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: New England Conservatory Intercultural Institute- Intensive Klezmer Workshop; Car ride to NY from workshop.; Alpert 202-203; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I, February 20, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0117; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Sarah Ferholt, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 204; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- II, February 20, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0118; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Sarah Ferholt, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 205; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I, March 23, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0119; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 206-207; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I (Copy), March 23, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0660; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 206-207; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I, April 8, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0120; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert, Joel Berkowitz, Jeff Wollock.; Recording location: Brooklyn.; Alpert 208-209; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I (Copy), April 8, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0661; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert, Joel Berkowitz, Jeff Wollock.; Recording location: Brooklyn.; Alpert 208-209; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- II, April 8, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0121; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert, Joel Berkowitz, Jeff Wollock.; Recording location: Brooklyn.; Alpert 210-211; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- II (Copy), April 8, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0662; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert, Joel Berkowitz, Jeff Wollock.; Recording location: Brooklyn.; Alpert 210-211; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman- I, August 3, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0122; Personnel: Geran Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 212-213; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman- I (Copy), August 3, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0663; Personnel: Geran Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 212-213; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman- II, August 3, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0123; Personnel: Geran Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 214; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman- II (Copy), August 3, 1995, AFC 2017/048: SR0664; Personnel: Geran Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 214; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I, April 23, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0124; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Kurt Bjorling, Jeff Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 215-216; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- II, April 23, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0125; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Kurt Bjorling, Jeff Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 217; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I, January 9, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0126; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Jeff Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 218-219; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I (Copy), January 9, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0665; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Jeff Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 218-219; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- I (Copy), January 9, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0666; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Jeff Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 218-219; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn- II, January 9, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0127; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Jeff Wollock, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 220-221; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- I, March 12, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0128; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 222; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- I (Copy), March 12, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0667; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 222; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- II; German Goldenshteyn and Teresa Yelizarova, March 12, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0129; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 223-224; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- II; German Goldenshteyn and Teresa Yelizarova (Copy), March 12, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0668; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 223-224; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rykielman, March 15, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0130; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rykielman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 225; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn, May 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0131; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 226-227; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- I, May 20, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0132; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 228-229; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- I (Copy), May 20, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0669; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 228-229; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- II, May 20, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0133; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 230-231; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- I, December 11, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0134; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Eve Jochnowitz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 232-233; 1 sound cassette
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn- II, December 11, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0135; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Eve Jochnowitz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 234; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman- I, March 31, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0136; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rykielman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 235-236; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rikelman- II, March 31, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0137; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rykielman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 237-238; 1 sound cassette
  - David Stepanovsky, German Goldenshteyn, January 7-April 19, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: David Stepanovsky, German Goldenshteyn, Sandler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 252; 1 WAV
  - Jeremy Grant, German Goldenshteyn, June 9, 2006, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Jeremy Grant, German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Moscow.; Alpert 255; 1 WAV
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn, January 6, 2006, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Mina Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 258; 1 WAV
  - German Goldenshteyn, September 22, 2003, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: New York City.; Alpert 273; 1 WAV
  - German Goldenshteyn, Jeff Warschauer, May 30, 2003, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Jeff Warschauer, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: German's house.; Alpert 274; 1 WAV
  - Yiddish Folksingers, October 22, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0372; Personnel: Yanker Gorelick, Elliot Eisenbach, Nathan Stuller, Janet Leuchter, Chana Luntz, Rabbi Shlomo Hochberg, Lisa Mayer, Zachary Mayer, Itzik Gottesman, Ken Richmond, German Goldenshteyn.; Alpert 720-721; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0407; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Jeff Walleck, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 776-777; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, May 5, 2002, AFC 2017/048: SR0588; Alpert 1085; 1 minidisc
  - Muzica Romaneasca, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0607; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn.; Alpert 1115-1116; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn-IIB, January 9, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0626; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn.; Alpert 1156; 1 sound cassette; There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - German and Mina Goldenshteyn, Hersch Rykielman, March 15, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0627; Alpert 1157; 1 sound cassette; There is no digital surrogate for this recording.
  - Digital surrogates of recordings in Series 3, 1988-2006, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 55 WAV, 55 MP3, 27 PDF
- Series 4: Ben Bazyler recordings
  Interviews and lessons with Ben Bazyler (1922-1990), a klezmer drummer and badkhn (a traditional wedding performer). Bazyler performed as a guest artist on the 1990 album Klezmer Music from Alpert's ensemble, Brave Old World. Alpert also wrote an article about Bazyler, published in the book American Klezmer: Its Roots and Offshoots by Mark Slobin.
  - Ben Bazyler, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0190; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Los Angeles.; Alpert 382; 1 sound cassette
  - Kapelye Work Tape; Ben Bazyler, June 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0191; Personnel: Kapelye.; Alpert 383-384; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler, December 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0193; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 387-388; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- II, December 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0197; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 395; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- I, May 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0199; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 398-399; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- II, May 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0200; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 400-401; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- III, May 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0201; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 402-403; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- III (Copy), May 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0670; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 402-403; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- I, May 30, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0206; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 414-415; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- II, May 30, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0207; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 416; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- II (Copy), May 30, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0675; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 416; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler, August 27, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0644; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Ben Bazyler's home, 828 N. Hayworth Ave, Los Angeles, CA 90046.; Alpert 417-418; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler (Copy), August 27, 1988, AFC 2017/48: SR0676; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Ben Bazyler's home, 828 N. Hayworth Ave, Los Angeles, CA 90046.; Alpert 417-418; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0209; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 421-422; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- I (Copy), undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0677; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 421-422; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- II, August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0210; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 423; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- II (Copy), August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0678; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 423; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- III, August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0212; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 424-425; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- III (Copy), August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0679; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 424-425; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- IV, August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0213; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 426-427; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Beregovski- IV (Copy), August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0680; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 426-427; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler Passover Tape, Alpert Answering Machine, 1989-1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0221; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 440-441; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler, February-March 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0222; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 442; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- I, February 26, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0223; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 443-444; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- II, February 26, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0224; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 445; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- III, February 27, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0225; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 446-447; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler, March 4-5, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0226; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 448-449; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- II, March 5-6, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0227; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 450-451; 1 sound cassette
  - Ben Bazyler- I, March 5, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0228; Personnel: Ben Bazyler, Dina Halpern.; Alpert 452-453; 1 sound cassette
  - Digital surrogates of recordings in Series 4, 1984-1996, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 38 WAV, 38 MP3, 21 PDF
- Series 5: Soviet Jewish Folk Arts Program recordings
  Interviews with performers in the Soviet Jewish Folk Arts Program. Artists include Bronya Sakina, Iosif Glushkin, Tanya Lebedinskaya, Gennady Gutkin, Fanya Moshinskaya, Zyama Epshteyn, Semyon Kommisar, Borekh Shildergemeyn, Yeva Chornaya, Yefim Libovich, Khaya Sherman, Boris Legun, and Eliza Efremashvili.
  - SJFAP V, Gennady Guthin; Ukrainian Clarinetist, May 4-27, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0143; Personnel: Gennady Guthin, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 248-249; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP VII, Borekh Shildergemeyn; Isaak Levovich Varshavsky, May 6-10, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0144; Personnel: Borekh Shildergemeyn, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Queens.; Alpert 250-251; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP VII, Bronx B'day Party; SJFAP VIII, Sore and Shome Tservil, May 27-29, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0145; Personnel: Michael Alpert, many others.; Recording location: Russian Center, Bronx.; Alpert 253-254; 1 sound cassette
  - Side A: SJFAP IX, Bronya Sakina, May 25, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0146; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Bensonhurst.; Alpert 256-257; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP X, Mikhail Bleykhman, Yusif Glushkin; SJFAP X, Yusif Glushkin, June 1, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0147; Personnel: Mikhail Bleykhman, Yusif Glushkin, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 260-261; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XI, Ina's Family, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0148; Personnel: Ina's Family, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 264-265; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XII, Borekh Shildergemeyn; SJFAP XII, Borekh Shildergemeyn, Albert and Sonja Gorelashvili, August 2, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0149; Personnel: Borekh Shildergemeyn, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home in Queens.; Alpert 266-267; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XIII, Mariam and Oren Merkher; SJFAP XIII, Iosef Dreyzin, August 16-26, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0150; Personnel: Mariam Merkher, Oren Merkher, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Brooklyn.; Alpert 270-271; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XIIIA, Iosef Dreyzin, October 14, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0151; Personnel: Iosef Dreyzin, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 274-275; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XIV, Leonid Verbitsky, August 30, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0152; Personnel: Leonid Verbitsky, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Coney Island; Alpert 278-279; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XV, Leonid Verbitsky, August 30, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0153; Personnel: Leonid Verbitsky, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Coney Island; Alpert 280; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XVI, Rozet, September 10, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0154; Personnel: Rozet, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Brooklyn (home).; Alpert 281-282; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XVI, Yura Shvartsmann, September 10, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0155; Personnel: Yura Shvartsmann, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Brooklyn.; Alpert 283-284; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XVIII, Shifra Shifrina, September 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0156; Personnel: Shifra Shifrina, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Brooklyn.; Alpert 288; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XIX, Sirotina, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0157; Personnel: Sirotina.; Alpert 289-290; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP XX, Eliza Efremashvili and Mother; SJFAP XX, Gregorian Program Rehearsal, November 12, 1982 - February 27, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0158; Personnel: Eliza Efremashvili and Mother, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Queens (home).; Alpert 291-292; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP VI, Georgian Synagogue, May 6, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0159; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Georgian Synagogue, Queens, New York.; Alpert 296-297; 1 sound cassette
  - SJFAP I - Russian Jewish Singers, March 1981 -May 14, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0309; Personnel: Arkady Segal, Iosif Glushkin, Tanya Lebedinskaya, Michael Alpert, Alexander Syrotin.; Recording location: Brighton Beach.; Alpert 320-321; 1 sound cassette
  - Digital surrogates of recordings in Series 5, 1982-1983, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 34 WAV, 34 MP3, 18 PDF
- Series 6: Eastern Europe field recordings